So tonight I'll sing a song to all my friends
Also to those we won't be seeing again
The Count of Monte Cristo
To those I knew and those I still adore
And I want to see once more
I just pray that you will love me and trust me
Laugh with me and cry with me
Spend those silent times with me
Love me ever more
You and I were lovers
Our dreams were not soured by life
And then my friends' betrayal
Meant you never would be my wife
Harsh words were said
And lies were told instead
I didn't ever mean to make you cry
Ladies and gentlemen, good evening.
A rage that is only permitted by youth.
A pure, unadulterated rage.
That is the most appropriate description
...for the emotion expressed by the young soul.
How exquisite it is!
How I desire it!
More! More!
Act 18:
The Duel
C'mon, baby, why not?
Is it because you are a soldier's son that you did not give in to fear and run away?
En garde!
Edmond... is dead.
This body retains only his shape and appearance.
There is no longer anything of Edmond himself left within it.
I will show you proof that Edmond, the man you once loved, is now dead.
Edmond...
It's done!
I'm cutting it pretty close...
I wrote a message in a birthday card for him,
...but I think we're too old for that kind of thing, so I feel awkward giving it to him in person.
Anyway, give it to Albert after I leave tomorrow.
Please?
I'm begging you.
He should just be a man and give it to him himself...
I don't believe it...
It can't be!
Not so fast, Madame!
This can't be...
He's only a...
Edmond!
I'm sorry, Madame, but I can't let you do that.
Please, let me go! I have a duty to keep that boy safe!
Please understand, this is a duel.
A formal duel, in which Monsieur Albert challenged the Count.
Albert is... Albert is still a child!
Call it off!
No, Madame. Monsieur Albert holds the rank of viscount.
In the eyes of the law, this duel is completely legitimate.
Edmond!
Please, stop!
Your feelings...
Your pain...
Your loneliness...
I'll... I'll bear the brunt of all of it!
Stop!
STOP!
Countess Morcerf!
Watch closely!
Watch as I prove to you that
Edmond Dantes is dead!
Please, stop...
Please!
STOP!
Oh, crap!
Why didn't you wake me up?!
Franz!
Fran...
He wouldn't...!
This is what I've been waiting for...
To become Gankutsuou is to lose your humanity.
As the composition of his entire body is being replaced with crystal,
...the temperature of his heart drops and drops,
...until it, too, is eventually lost.
The instant he is released from his suffering, he will also lose his emotions.
Anger... sadness...
hatred...
He will lose them all.
That is what he fears above all else.
That is why his heart is the last part of him.
If he still retains even fragments of human emotion,
...his heart alone will be vulnerable.
Gankutsuou, come closer...
That's right...
Come straight at me.
Franz...
Franz!
I will now prove who the victor is...
Right here and now!
You were cursed since birth,
...born from the union of that cowardly traitor Fernand Mondego and Mercedes.
You, who have walked in the sunlight your entire life, could not possibly know...
...the tale of the innocent man who had his youth stolen away from him,
...and the old man who fell victim to loneliness and starvation!
Fate has now come full circle, and the curse is about to reach its fruition!
Curse your fate, and your parents, as you die by my sword!
Don't do it!
FRANZ!
I sure hope he likes it...
Albert...
The... The doctor's gonna be here soon, so hang in there...
Boy, you were out cold last night...
Those pills worked pretty good, didn't they?
Why? Why did you do it?
I'm sorry... that things turned out this way...
But you taught me how to handle a sword, so I put up a pretty good fight...
That's enough!
Don't... Don't try to talk.
Idiot... You think you can boss me around?
Franz!
Albert...
I had a dream last night...
Maybe it was last year...
Or was it the year before last?
The two of us and Eugenie went to Normandy together, remember?
No, or was it in the south of France?
The three of us sprawled out on the beach,
...and we celebrated your birthday.
It was so windy that when we tried to eat a piece of cheese, it tasted like sand...
And Eugenie's favorite hat blew away...
She was really depressed about it, remember?
Happy birthday...
Congratulations on turning sixteen...
Franz, hang on a little longer...
The doctor's gonna be here any minute now, okay?
You're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be okay, so hang on.
Say, Franz?
It's nice and warm out here, isn't it?
Franz?
FRANZ!
I'm not the man I used to be
And what you see is not what it seems
I traveled through space to be with you here
What you don't know, you shouldn't fear
You won't see me coming...
Till I strike
Alone, I walk through the darkness of the night...
...as I wait for the sun.
Next time on Gankutsuou,
The Count of Monte Cristo, act 19:
Act 19:
Even if I Should Stop Being Me
..."Even if I Should Stop Being Me".
Bide your time, and hold out hope!