So tonight I'll sing a song to all my friends
Also to those we won't be seeing again
The Count of Monte Cristo
To those I knew and those I still adore
And I want to see once more
I just pray that you will love me and trust me
Laugh with me and cry with me
Spend those silent times with me
Love me ever more
You and I were lovers
Our dreams were not soured by life
And then my friends' betrayal
Meant you never would be my wife
Harsh words were said
And lies were told instead
I didn't ever mean to make you cry
Ladies and gentlemen, good evening.
When he visits his fiancée,
...the young man saw a young woman struggling to fight destiny.
However,
...none of them are yet aware of the cruel fate
...that is silently bearing down on them.
Act 7:
The Secret Flower Garden
Hey!
Count!
Albert.
What happened?
She isn't feeling well.
Haidee is unaccustomed to crowds.
You needn't concern yourself.
We will meet again.
Let's go back in.
Okay?
I wonder what it was that Haidee saw?
She looked as if she...
You saw him?
You saw that man?
I've heard that you are engaged to be married...
Yes.
Are you happy?
I... I don't think I will be able to restrain myself tonight.
I'm sorry.
Please excuse me.
I wonder if Haidee is okay?
Who cares about the
Count's mistress?
She isn't like that.
He cares for her.
Like a master is kind towards his pet dog.
Don't put the Count on the same level as people like that!
The Count and Haidee have...
Um...
A relationship as two independent adults.
Where they both care for each other and...
Forget about other people.
What about you?
How do you feel about Eugenie?
You're not one to talk.
"The aristocracy doesn't marry for love, they marry for money and honor."
Is what Maximilien said still bothering you?
He was right. As much as I hate to admit it.
That's how marriages work, you know?
I'm not getting married because I want to, either.
Baron Franz d'Epinay!
I'd like a word.
Why aren't you with your fiancée?
How is that any of your business?
Don't you love her?!
I like her.
I like her as just another girl.
How can you talk like that?!
Wait a minute, Maximilien!
Let me handle this. Okay?
If she's your fiancée,
you should love her with all your heart!
You didn't have to say it like that.
I said what was on my mind, that's all.
You're too irresponsible.
You're always like that.
I guess I'm no different.
I've never been in love with someone, not like he is.
Albert, what do you think it
means to be in love with someone?
It's nothing but trouble.
I'll let you do what you can to straighten this out.
What? Hey!
Wait!
Let's do it.
I can't go through with it...
What are you talking about?
Just do it like we planned, and you'll do fine!
First off, you compliment her!
Compliment her?
On what?
On anything! Her dress!
Her makeup!
That's Crown Prosecutor Villefort.
He's Valentine's father.
Isn't he scary?
Even small-time crooks get the death penalty when he gets his hands on them.
That's Valentine's mother.
They're not related by blood, though.
Edouard! Come here this instant!
Edouard, her younger brother.
He and Valentine have different mothers.
I don't wanna!
Take a look. Aren't these beautiful horses?
I hate horses!
I'm sorry, he can be such a handful.
I'm so embarrassed.
Is Valentine coming?
That girl seems to prefer staying at home.
I hate Valentine, too!
They'll be coming soon.
It's nothing, Grandfather.
Mademoiselle, the Viscount Albert de Morcerf is here to see you.
Hi.
About last night...
I think he has something that he wants to say to you.
Go on.
Um...
I'm sorry, I have to prepare my grandfather's dinner...
Hey! Wait!
I'm in...
I've fallen in love with you!
I love you!
Geez, our plans have gone out the window!
That's enough from you! I'll talk to her first, so you go wait over there!
I love you!
I think she knows that!
I'm sorry if we startled you.
This wasn't what we had in mind.
He must have been making fun of me.
No! He meant it!
What's this all about?
Why now?
Maximilien meant what he said.
He's just a little... clumsy at expressing himself.
I don't want to hear what he has to say. I'm already...
Franz has told me how he feels.
He says that he only thinks of you as the fiancée chosen for him by his parents.
But you feel the same way, don't you?
That's why he says you should do what you want.
He might not have a title, but Maximilien is a fine soldier and an honest man.
And most important of all, he's deeply in love with you.
I'm sure that he'll make you...
Please leave.
No one... No one considers what I want.
Valentine...
Get out.
I will now pass judgment.
The defendant is found guilty of the crimes of larceny and insulting the aristocracy, and is hereby sentenced to death.
There were extenuating circumstances!
You'll get no sympathy from me!
Trash like you disturb the public order of the kingdom...
You have a visitor.
Hey. Do you miss the outside world?
Are you getting along with Valentine?
I've heard that you beat her severely.
Who on earth told you that?!
It's just a rumor.
I like to think that I'm attentive as can be to that girl.
Just because she's the daughter of
his old wife doesn't mean that l...
Driver? Aren't we going a little too fast?
It's not me, Madame!
The horses!
They aren't obeying me!
You are not harmed,
I trust?
Why, it's the Count of Monte Cristo!
We have you to thank for our lives.
It was fortunate indeed that I had on hand one who is skilled in the handling of horses.
You look weird!
Are you an alien?
Don't be such a rascal!
Curiosity is a sign of intelligence.
We still don't know your name...
This is the Count of Monte Cristo.
He and my husband are practically family.
I heard something about you buying the late Prince's booth at the opera...
How embarrassing.
It is not my custom to attract undue attention to myself,
...but there were no other seats to be had.
This is Héloise, the wife of
Crown Prosecutor Villefort.
Then one might say that you are the wife of Paris' guardian angel.
You're such a flatterer.
Your horses still seem to be agitated.
Allow us to return you to your homes.
If the good Madame Villefort is amenable,
I shall see to it personally.
Oh, my...
I've never seen her like that before.
Madame has returned!
Maximilien! Hurry!
Barrois! Tea for our guest!
Please, that won't be necessary, Madame.
Please, call me Héloise, Count.
Valentine! We have a visitor!
Mademoiselle says that she is feeling unwell.
Honestly, that girl...
Valentine!
Can't you even come out
and say hello to our guest?!
Valentine!
She is utterly miserable.
Maybe you're right.
I can tell.
Deep down, her heart yearns for freedom.
But she is averting her eyes from those feelings.
You might be right.
She is delicate and fragile!
Can't you hear her soul crying out?!
I can hear it, all right.
It says, "No one considers what I want".
I don't. Neither do you.
None of us do.
That girl is always making trouble for me.
Perhaps she gets it from her late mother.
She's sickly and stays cooped up indoors.
I'm trying my best to raise her to be more sociable, but...
"She's gonna die young."
Isn't that what you said, Mama?
Edouard! You and your nonsense!
I feel sorry for my own child, too.
Valentine stands to inherit the fortune of her grandfather, Monsieur Noirtier,
...as well has that of the Marquis Saint-Meran
on her mother's side,
...but this boy will receive nothing.
It saddens me to hear that.
Siblings should be equally fortunate,
even if unrelated by blood.
He's got fangs like a vampire!
Edouard!
You're making me angry!
Vampire! Vampire!
He's a blue-faced vampire!
I'm sorry, he's such a rude boy...
Not at all, he is a darling child.
To apologize for his behavior, shall
I show you to my secret place?
It's a modest little refuge.
I'm worried about her.
But there is nothing that
I can do for her...
What is it?
So, this greenhouse is your refuge...
It is magnificent.
You flatter me.
These flowers might be my only friends.
Belladonna. Mandragora. Datura.
Your favorite flowers all share
a fascinating trait, Madame.
What might that be?
In each of them, their beautiful petals conceal a deadly poison.
I had no idea...
Hey!
My love of horticulture grew into an interest in botany.
It isn't a woman's place to be interested in such things.
Could it be that you also have an interest in toxicology?
Why would I be interested in such horrible things?
Horrible? Why should it be horrible?
Toxicology and pharmacology are two sides of the same coin.
Also, nothing is more enticing to human beings than poison.
Am I mistaken?
Poisons that steal a man's life away in an instant.
Poisons that kill slowly and leave no trace of itself.
One must wonder how many poisonings...
...have been consigned to the darkness, known to no one.
And one more thing.
There is a beauty to those who have been captivated by poison's charms.
Hey! Gentlemen don't peep into other people's windows!
This trinket is commonly referred to as a Borgia Ring.
Come. Press on the stone and see what happens.
It is said that Lucrezia Borgia used
these to dispatch countless people.
And among her victims was her own husband...
That ring belongs to you, Madame.
I'm so happy...
It is nothing, a mere getting-acquainted gift.
Grandfather...
I want to go somewhere far away.
To some faraway place where no one knows who I am.
It's nothing but trouble.
Benedetto! Take a look out the left window.
That's Viscount Albert de Morcerf.
I'm not the man I used to be
And what you see is not what it seems
I traveled through space to be with you here
What you don't know, you shouldn't fear
You won't see me coming...
Till I strike
A party at the Count's villa.
In the labyrinth, we cross paths with a beautiful, horrible past.
Next time on Gankutsuou,
The Count of Monte Cristo, act 8:
Act 8:
A Night in Boulogne
..."A Night in Boulogne".
Bide your time, and hold out hope!