Albert!
This isn't over yet!
Eat this!
Albert!
Father...
The Count of Monte Cristo
I bid you welcome to my palace!
You!
Edmond?
W-Where'd you go?!
Where are you?!
Show yourself!
Fernand Mondego!
Allow me to express my sincerest gratitude for attacking in person, my good former General.
Vile apparition!
Those words will be the last you ever speak!
I will give you the despair of one who has had everything stolen from him.
Prepare to taste the depths of my vengeance!
Act 23:
Edmond Dantes
Don't push yourself too hard.
Where's Mother?!
We managed to pull her back from the brink.
We're keeping her doped up for now.
Baptistin! Can this ship still fly?!
Yeah, barely.
Hurry, take us to the
Champs Elysées!
My father wants to kill the Count!
Lifting off immediately.
Setting course for the Count's manor!
Baptistin, you've got things covered down there, right?
You bet! Do your thing, big guy!
Count!
Hurry! You must take your medicine!
That will not... be necessary, Haidee.
My pact with Gankutsuou is inviolate.
My body is no longer my own.
No, Count! You are yourself!
You are the only person in this world that I adore.
Your words... no longer reach me.
My only desire is to carry out my final revenge.
I will not allow you to die.
Not like my father did... Never!
Damn you!
Set your mind at ease.
I will not kill you.
I will not give you respite so easily!
You nightmare... begone!
H-How?
How can this be?!
I will not die.
I am not even permitted death.
S-Stay away!
Stay away from me!
Fernand... Look upon me.
Look upon the man who has sacrificed himself, body and soul, for the sake of his revenge!
You mustn't!
You mustn't go any further!
I cannot allow you to take this any further.
Stand aside.
I will not.
Stand aside!
I will not!
Because I... I love you.
I do not want to lose the one I love like I did that day.
Even if I must forfeit my life here!
You heard her, Edmond.
Her Highness says that she will sacrifice her life for you.
Hey!
Father!
Father! Stop!
Don't do it!
Drop that sword right now, you hear?
If you don't, she's dead!
Count, please... Your medicine!
You and your "revenge"!
You and your "judgment"!
This is why you've always been a hopeless weakling!
Highness, you got a little too carried away.
Shall I have you pay the price for that right here and now?
Fernand. I suggest you look to your son.
You bastard!
Your son's life is mine for the taking.
Bertuccio. Pull the trigger.
Have you gone crazy?!
Go ahead, I dare you to touch that trigger!
She'll follow right on his heels!
Stop it! Don't do it, Father!
Edmond! Give it up!
Don't try to pretend to be tough!
You're too easygoing for that!
Let go of my son!
Bertuccio, don't do this! Don't you care what happens to her?!
The man... The man I serve is...
Father... Don't hurt anyone but me.
Please, don't hurt her any more...
Edmond! Please, let my son go!
He's the only thing I have left that's precious to me.
Please, don't take him from me!
Hate me!
Hate ME!
I'll give you my life if that's what you want!
But please, don't take his.
I'm begging you, Edmond!
Anything but my son's life!
Kill me! Kill me!
Fernand...
I'm so sorry.
Death is the ultimate end of all things.
But in the end, it is nothing but a release from suffering.
What I want from you is despair.
I want your everlasting despair.
It is time.
No! Don't!
Baptistin!
What am I doing on the ground?
Baptistin! Why did you do that?
No! I don't want you to die!
Quit your bawling... I'm just a little sleepy, that's all...
Count, what do you want so badly that you're willing to hurt innocent people to get it?!
And YOU! What the hell is so important that you'd even kill Mother and Haidee to get it?!
What's more important to you two than people's lives?!
No matter how much you try to justify it, murder is still murder!
Count, Father, all you two are doing is running away!
All you're doing is deluding yourselves by refusing to back down to each other!
You claim to understand what my friend feels inside?
You think that you understand my poor friend's feelings?
Well, I...
The pact is concluded.
No!
My name is...
Gankutsuou.
Bertuccio! Fetch me my cloak!
Count! Is this the "destiny" you spoke of?!
Weren't you the one who told me that destiny was something...
...that you create for yourself with your own two hands?!
Where is your will now?
Where have you gone?
Count!
His time has run out.
You cannot save him.
Not you, a boy who does not understand my friend's heart.
I might not understand the Count's true feelings, but I...
Count?!
I'm... going to kill you!
I'm going to...
Count!
Damn it!
No!
Count, no!
Count!
I cannot die...
Not until he dies at my hand...
Please, don't talk!
Where is he?
Where is Albert?!
I'm... I'm right here!
Bring me my sword, Bertuccio...
Bring me my sword of vengeance... Put it in my hand...
I must kill him...
Count, I give you my word.
Even if the future is shrouded in darkness, and even if despair is raining down on me,
...I will go on living, no matter what!
Just as you did!
I want you to remember something for me...
My name is... Edmond Dantes.
Haidee.
I will not leave.
I will remain with the Count.
If you wish to flee, feel free to do so. But as for me, l...
Idiot! Do you really believe that the Count wants you to die?!
Didn't you hear him? He said, "I want you to remember my name".
Haidee, you have to live!
You have to leave this place and live!
Father, let's go!
I have always aspired to two things.
To be nobler than the nobility.
And to be a finer soldier than any other.
But in the end, it was an egotistical wish that glossed over the lies underneath.
Father!
There will be no more running away for me, Albert.
Now, go! Hurry!
Keep her safe!
Hurry!
Run. Keep running!
Ever forward.
Edmond...
Albert!
Jump!
Excuse me.
Shout out my name.
Seek out my soul.
My name is Gankutsuou!
And I am always with you.
I'm not the man I used to be
And what you see is not what it seems
I traveled through space to be with you here
What you don't know, you shouldn't fear
You won't see me coming...
Till I strike
Final Act:
At the Shore