So tonight I'll sing a song to all my friends
Also to those we won't be seeing again
The Count of Monte Cristo
To those I knew and those I still adore
And I want to see once more
I just pray that you will love me and trust me
Laugh with me and cry with me
Spend those silent times with me
Love me ever more
You and I were lovers
Our dreams were not soured by life
And then my friends' betrayal
Meant you never would be my wife
Harsh words were said
And lies were told instead
I didn't ever mean to make you cry
Get your moccoletti!
How 'bout a moccoletto!
Act 1:
At Journey's End, We Meet
Franz!
Why, hello, Marquise!
When did you arrive on Luna?
I made a loop around the inner planets.
I arrived only yesterday.
I see. You arrived just in time
to catch the end of Carnival.
And by the way...
Who is this?
Ma'am!
My traveling companion, as well as my best friend.
Viscount Albert de Morcerf.
I am pleased to make your acquaintance, Madame.
My... You're the son of General Morcerf.
Well, well...
Is this your first time on Luna?
I suggest you enjoy yourself, then.
This is a city where all your desires can be fulfilled, no matter what they may be.
Apparently, he styles himself a count.
But I'm not so sure.
Regardless, Luna's high society has been abuzz with rumors about him this past month.
There are some who say that he's a nouveau riche who made his fortune on the frontier, or that he's an alien from outer space,
...or even that he's a monster
in human form, or a vampire.
That might be going a little far...
Excuse me, but what is he called?
What is his name?
The Count of Monte Cristo.
"Death is certain, its hour uncertain."
Are you sure you weren't dreaming or something? Daydreaming or whatever?
Get serious. This proves that it was real.
And?
I'm gonna use it to make his acquaintance.
To meet the Count.
Are you crazy?
It's a huge hassle.
Don't do it. You have no idea
who this guy really is.
You think so?
Sure I do!
Begging monsieur's pardon, but are you
Viscount Morcerf from room 405?
Y-Yes.
Yes, that's me.
I have a message from my master,
the Count of Monte Cristo.
Well? What do you think?
What do I think of what?
Why would he want to talk to two complete strangers like us?
His note said that he wanted to establish friendly relations with fellow aristocrats who were staying in the same hotel, didn't it?
What a coincidence...
I'm not so sure.
There you go again.
You're such a worrywart.
At least stay and have dinner with the man.
I have some doubts about whether this guy is even a real aristocrat.
This is Luna, remember?
He's almost certainly a con-
How do you do, messieurs. I am called the Count of Monte Cristo.
Thank you for coming.
Come now, this won't do.
When a man has come all the way to Luna, he simply must try these dishes.
Are you sure? We're the only ones who are eating.
You haven't touched anything all through dinner.
Please, you needn't concern yourselves about me.
Just as journeys traveled alone are dull, daily meals eaten alone have no flavor.
For me, speaking with guests as I am now is the greatest feast I could wish for.
Please, help yourselves.
Incidentally, what did you think of the opera today?
Speaking for myself, I don't
normally see operas very often,
...but I couldn't help being drawn into the story!
Oh, I see.
So, Monsieur Albert, are you saying that you have someone...
...whom you pine away for, just as in the play?
No, of course not!
Come on, 'fess up.
Eugenie and I were chosen for each other by our parents.
I've never been in love like the main character of that opera.
It's the same with everything else in my life.
Something that I can lose myself in.
Something that will grab my heart and never let go.
I set out on this journey to find that something.
Why are you trying to make it sound so noble?
As I recall, the goal of this little quest had more to do with what's below your waist.
Franz! Cut it out!
Oh, youth is a wonderful thing.
Endless possibilities. Hopes.
And ardent passion.
Count, have you ever been in love like that?
I have.
What sort of woman was she?
Hey! Don't be rude!
To be honest, I, too, once had
feelings for a certain woman.
As well as dreams of a future with this woman.
However...
...all of them ended as nothing more than dreams.
In short, those dreams were only dreams.
And in those dreams' stead stands the man that I have become.
Bertuccio!
Coffee for our guests.
At once.
I thank you for the honor of your company tonight.
Not at all, sir!
The honor was ours!
I would like you to join me for luncheon on my balcony tomorrow. What say you?
Really?
We'd be honored to...
We're terribly sorry, Count.
We appreciate your kind offer, but we couldn't possibly accept.
Luna's public executions
are the highlight of Carnival.
The festivities reach their peak as the blood of heinous criminals...
...washes away the crowd's sins.
One cannot speak of experiencing Luna's
Carnival without having seen this spectacle.
Is that not so,
Monsieur Albert?
Y-Yes, sir.
You're exactly right, Count!
In that case, I shall await you here in this room again tomorrow.
Pleasant dreams to both of you.
Hey! Albert!
Yeah?
What's the matter?
You don't look so good.
It was cold.
His hand was as cold as ice...
It was like a corpse's hand...
Who are today's condemned?
One is a man who committed murder out of poverty.
One is a man who committed murder over a love affair.
And the third is a man who slaughtered an entire family to steal their possessions.
All three are heinous criminals who are beyond forgiveness.
I did it to feed my family!
I had to!
My beloved wife and child, please forgive me!
Please, spare me...
Stop that!
Stop it at once!
My Lord Cardinal!
I didn't murder anyone!
My rival framed me!
I'm innocent!
Please, undo these chains!
You have to believe me!
I bet they're just saying anything that might earn them a reprieve.
I didn't do it!
I didn't do anything!
You moron!
Shut your trap!
I'm sick of you and your damn whining!
As for me, I killed ten people!
Women and children,
I killed 'em all!
How's that?! Live it up, you bastards!
C'mon! I wanna see some more happy faces out there!
Today's card is most entertaining.
What say you?
Why don't we have a bit of sport with this?
A sideshow to the execution, as it were.
I have here a single letter.
It is a letter of pardon that
was given to me by the Cardinal.
How in the world did you get something like that?
Unfortunately, I have but this one letter of pardon.
To make the choice an impartial one,
...I have written the initials of one of the condemned men on each card.
Now, please choose one of them.
Come now, it's nothing more than a little game.
Just a minute, Count!
If that's the case, shouldn't we hear what they have to say first?!
My good Monsieur Franz, we are not judges.
Regardless of what we do, they are going to die.
I merely suggest that we make use of that fact in order to enjoy ourselves.
At this moment, we have in our hands the power to offer the hand of salvation to them.
Why do you hesitate to make
use of that power to do good?
Yes, it almost feels as if one
has become God, does it not?
What are you thinking?!
You're using people's lives as a game?! You're crazy!
Come on, let's go.
Albert!
A game?
Yes, it is a game.
Our own lives are pieces that are toyed with as part of someone else's game.
Has it ever seemed that way to you?
I wouldn't know.
Let's go!
Come on!
I was of the opinion that you and
I would be friends, Monsieur Albert.
This is most disappointing.
You set out on your journey in order to find something.
To find and grab hold of a new you.
Through the exertion of your own will.
Come on, Albert, let's go!
Albert!
I'll... I'll do it!
Don't do it!
You'll be sorry you did!
It's just a game.
Isn't it, Count?
No! No!
Albert...
No!
Albert!
A pardon has been issued by the Cardinal!
The condemned man who is to be pardoned is...
...Rocca Briori,
also known as Peppino!
How do ya like that?!
Thank you!
Thanks oh so much!
Long live His Excellency the Cardinal!
Monsieur Albert, you have done a good deed.
Truly a good deed.
Now, the show is beginning.
Kill him! Kill him!
You mustn't look away,
Monsieur Albert.
Not for an instant.
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Don't hold back,
Baptistin.
Please forgive me.
My vengeance...
...is now set in motion.
Hey, let's go to a cafe or something to clear our heads.
Or how about hitting the red-light district?
Oh, right. I forgot. Sorry about that.
You hate that sort of thing, don't you?
I guess there's always the casino...
Please, don't talk to me about gambling!
What's gotten into you?
You were the one who was dying to see it in the first place.
And then you let the Count talk you into...
I know that!
I know all that!
"I brought this on my own head, and that's why I'm angry! I'm angry at myself!" Right?
You're always fussing over me!
Are you my girlfriend?
Are you my mother?!
Are you?
I'm going back to the hotel to get ready for the ball.
What about you?
You alone?
Tonight is the last night of Carnival.
You shouldn't be alone on a night like this.
I want to be alone.
Today was the worst day of my life.
Albert...
Hey, don't be in such a rush...
Are you going to come?
I'm not the man I used to be
And what you see is not what it seems
I traveled through space to be with you here
What you don't know, you shouldn't fear
You won't see me coming...
Till I strike
A passing fling on Luna.
It was a trap set by bandits.
Moment by moment, the hour of death approaches.
Next time on Gankutsuou,
The Count of Monte Cristo, act 2:
Act 2:
Until the Sun Rises Over the Moon
..."Until the Sun
Rises Over the Moon".
Bide your time, and hold out hope!