So tonight I'll sing a song to all my friends
Also to those we won't be seeing again
The Count of Monte Cristo
To those I knew and those I still adore
And I want to see once more
I just pray that you will love me and trust me
Laugh with me and cry with me
Spend those silent times with me
Love me ever more
You and I were lovers
Our dreams were not soured by life
And then my friends' betrayal
Meant you never would be my wife
Harsh words were said
And lies were told instead
I didn't ever mean to make you cry
Ladies and gentlemen, good evening.
Everything lies in ruin.
What was once believed to be solid ground
...has opened up and swallowed everything.
The young soul wanders aimlessly,
...betrayed by everything he had believed in.
But what he clutches at in the end is...
Act 17:
The Confession
Someone taught me the meaning of the word hope.
Count, that someone was you!
Wait for me, Albert!
Mademoiselle.
A letter has arrived for you.
Thank you.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Why aren't you answering me?
My words now fall on deaf ears.
Is... Is that what you're trying to say?!
There is no such thing as coincidence.
I believe that is what I told you.
As I recall, it is the very first thing I told you.
Everything that happens does so out of necessity.
What are you trying to say?
Tell me, if Haidee were not a living witness to your father's true identity,
...what value would there be in keeping her with me?
Tell me, if you were not
Mondego's son,
...why would it have been necessary for me to meet you on Luna?
It can't be...
From the very beginning, you were using me?
Yes. I met you under the pretense of coincidence,
...and took advantage of this so-called
"friendship" that you have such faith in.
That is what
I am saying.
I even used props such as that watch.
It can't be...
From the very beginning, you were using me?
You're lying!
You're lying! You're lying!
I can't believe that everything has been a setup since the very beginning!
I can't!
I mean, haven't you always helped me, Count?
Haven't you always been looking out for me?
I don't believe that all the time we spent together was a lie!
Not one bit!
You poor, foolish boy.
You still wish to remain immersed
in those naive delusions of yours?
Is that what you are trying to say?
Even if I deliberately brought you with me on that pleasure cruise that day,
...knowing full well that Haidee was about to disclose the truth at the National Assembly?
I must thank you.
You have been most useful to me in the time we have known one another.
You have my gratitude.
From the bottom of my heart.
I challenge you!
My, how old-fashioned.
The son of a soldier must act in accordance with tradition?
Is that it?
The time will be tomorrow morning at five.
In the forest of Boulogne.
Weapons?
Armor and bare steel!
Very well.
Bertuccio.
You are my witness.
Did you see the whole challenge from beginning to end?
Y-Yes, Excellency!
Albert!
I accept your challenge.
In that case, we will meet at five tomorrow!
It will serve to freeze the memory of this day, this hour, in time.
A memory which belongs to us alone.
I must go see him.
Count, is there nothing I can do to stop this duel between you and Albert?
You told me that I am free.
That is what allowed me to live to this day without taking my own life.
But if you... If you were to perish,
...I would not be able to go on living, either.
Gankutsuou...
Wait... Not yet!
It is not yet time!
Franz?
Albert!
Franz...
You've always looked out for me,
...but I'd always plunge ahead with what
I was doing, ignoring your advice.
I'm sorry...
I'm so sorry, Franz.
I'm back.
Welcome home.
Geez, wipe the snot from your nose.
Get off my back!
You total idiot! You played straight into his hands!
You've got to call off this duel right now!
Cut it out!
You'll act as my second, right?
I don't blame you for being angry.
But this is one thing that I have to see through, no matter what!
Listen to me, and listen good.
The Count has been planning to kill you all along.
Are you saying that you don't care if you end up getting killed in the name of his revenge?!
Franz.
That bastard deceived me and used dirty tricks to lure me in.
He used the most despicable means imaginable to toy with me and turn my life upside-down.
And I can't... I can't let him get away with it!
Even if the Count used to be your mother's fiancé?
Your father was so in love with your mother...
...that 25 years ago, he framed the Count
for a crime he didn't commit...
...and took his fiancée away from him by force.
Edmond Dantes?
Mondego's wife is here to see you.
Edmond!
No, Count...
You are really Edmond Dantes, aren't you?
How I've missed you...
These past 25 years, I haven't forgotten you for an instant.
I know that you can never forgive what I've done.
But... But even if only once, I wish I could speak with you as Edmond!
Edmond... is dead.
This body retains only his shape and appearance.
There is no longer anything of Edmond himself left within it.
That's not true.
No, that isn't possible!
If that were so, why have I had the feeling ever since the day we met that you are Edmond?
You refuse to be disturbed by the coldness of my hand...
You leave me no choice, then.
I will show you proof that Edmond, the man you once loved, is now dead.
I will await you at five tomorrow morning in the forest of Boulogne.
It's already too late for that, Franz.
It's too late to do anything!
Whatever happened between the Count and our fathers in the past,
...I don't care about any of that anymore!
I can't take back what happened between the Count and me.
If he hates me that much, he should just kill me and be done with it!
Damn it!
He played games with my feelings!
Albert! Don't do it!
Don't go!
Come back!
Albert!
Please, come back...
You're still going to go see him, even knowing who he is?
Hi!
Franz! You're back!
Welcome home!
Is Albert here?
Uh... No, he was with me until a while ago.
He said that he had something to take care of.
Oh, he did?
Still, I'm glad to see you. I haven't been able to reach you since that day.
Sorry for worrying you.
Honestly! I was worried sick about you.
You timed your arrival perfectly, Franz.
Franz, don't you remember?
Tomorrow is Albert's birthday!
Yeah, exactly! That's why!
That's why I came to see you!
Geez, get your act together...
Actually, about that...
I wrote a song for Albert!
It's not finished yet, though.
Well?
Yeah, it's nice.
It's romantic.
Not like you at all.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Don't be rude!
That settles it! Tomorrow, you, Albert and I will have a party at our usual cafe!
But I can't...
Just say that a friend of yours is having a recital or something, and sneak out.
It'll all work out.
Okay, I get it.
So anyway, do you think you could do me a little favor?
As in?
I wrote a message in a birthday card for him,
...but I think we're too old for that kind of thing, so I feel awkward giving it to him in person.
Idiot, who cares how old you are?
You're just giving him a card.
Anyway, give it to Albert after I leave tomorrow.
Please?
I'm begging you.
It must be a surprise.
Sure, okay.
Okay, I think I'll keep working on that song for a while.
Don't work too hard.
See you tomorrow at 3 PM, then.
At our usual cafe.
Thanks for coming by to visit me today.
Excellency.
What is it?
Good luck.
Let's drink to victory with a red!
I'll have the white!
But that guy up there is pitch-black!
To victory!
Right!
I'm gonna mop the floor with that coward, just you watch!
The Count is no one to fear!
I'm not the man I used to be
And what you see is not what it seems
I traveled through space to be with you here
What you don't know, you shouldn't fear
You won't see me coming...
Till I strike
The clash of steel shatters the dawn silence.
Sword of righteous anger in hand,
I shall cut through all deception and lies!
Next time on Gankutsuou,
The Count of Monte Cristo, act 18:
..."The Duel".
Act 18:
The Duel
Bide your time, and hold out hope!