So tonight I'll sing a song to all my friends
Also to those we won't be seeing again
The Count of Monte Cristo
To those I knew and those I still adore
And I want to see once more
I just pray that you will love me and trust me
Laugh with me and cry with me
Spend those silent times with me
Love me ever more
You and I were lovers
Our dreams were not soured by life
And then my friends' betrayal
Meant you never would be my wife
Harsh words were said
And lies were told instead
I didn't ever mean to make you cry
Move it!
We've waited and waited, but she hasn't come back.
Fine, let her have it her way.
All right, you bums!
We're heading home!
Back to Luna!
All I could do was stand there and stare.
At the now masterless number 30, Champs Elysées.
At the city blocks that had crumbled away like sandcastles built on the beach.
At the silent blue sky that spread out above me.
That's right. The summer storm had come and gone.
Along with the end of our summer.
Final Act:
At the Shore
Five Years Later
Well, well, if it isn't the good Chief Secretary.
So, the Assistant Editor-in-Chief came in person, huh?
What a hard worker you are!
I was just worried about whether or not you're carrying out your duties properly.
So, how's the peace treaty coming along?
"Treaty Nearing Finalization At Long Last."
Something along those lines.
Thanks to this treaty, the restoration of diplomatic relations between our Kingdom...
...and the Empire is finally starting to look like a real possibility.
So, this marathon of a war is finally gonna end, huh?
Civilian interaction will become commonplace, and citizens of both nations will take each other by the hand.
We'll see the birth of a nation that's prosperous in the truest sense of the word.
Not a nation where only a select few prosper.
You know?
There's no telling when the times will change.
Even so, I want to believe in them.
I want to believe in the people who chose THIS solution at THIS time.
And that includes you.
Me, I just go with the flow with those times.
Well, let's leave the question of the truth of that statement for another time, okay?
Today's the day of our long-awaited reunion with those dear old friends of ours.
What's up?
Oh, damn!
Don't tell me you forgot to make reservations!
Sorry! Tell my secretary that I'll be late for the afternoon Cabinet meeting!
And tell her you're out making a reservation so important that you can't trust her to do it?
See you tonight at the Nouveau Casino!
We'll start off with a toast!
Too bad, I came all the way down here to show him this article...
Claire-Marie Eugenie's
Triumphant Return to Paris!
Max!
I'm home.
Julie! Julie!
Welcome home, Uncle Maximilien!
Spare me the "uncle" bit, okay?
Big brother! Thank goodness you're okay!
Did you behave yourselves and do what Emmanuel told you to do?
Of course we did!
You bet!
That's good. I have presents waiting for children who behaved themselves!
Yay!
That's our Uncle Max!
All right!
Big brother...
Maximilien!
Dear?
I'm home.
Valentine!
Maximilien!
I've returned, sir.
The peace that you dreamed of for so long between Earth and the Empire...
...is finally about to come to pass.
For that reason, I resigned from the military as of today.
The flow of goods traveling between Earth and the Empire will grow and grow.
So I intend to buy back my father's ship, the Pharaon, and help Emmanuel and Julie with the family business.
Maximilien...
Hey! Maximilien!
Valentine!
If we don't get moving soon, we'll be late for the party!
You have an eye for quality, sir!
That's an import item.
All the way from Earth.
It's a brand that's famous in Paris.
Would it look good on black hair?
These models from Earth certainly are pretty, aren't they?
Ah, here we are!
I'd say that it goes perfectly with black hair, wouldn't you?
Peppo!
Forget it.
I'll pass.
Wha...? But sir!
Forget it!
Forget it, forget it!
Trinkets like that aren't good enough for our Princess!
It will be a whole new you...
Thank you, Ali.
Would you care to join me, Bertuccio?
No, ma'am. I'm on guard duty.
I would like to show you something.
What's this?
It says that Monsieur Albert will be arriving here on the day of the coronation ceremony.
And that he will do so as a secretarial aide to Earth's ambassador.
Bertuccio, what would you call this, if not fate?
Our old master must have guided him here.
So that you would be able to fulfill your duties to the best of your ability, Princess.
Yes...
Yes!
I also wish to keep Janina safe, so that this peace endures for years to come.
That desire will never change.
And we will be there with you.
Thank you, Bertuccio.
Air France flight 1027 from Galileo to Paris Spaceport...
...will be entering Earth orbit momentarily.
Our estimated arrival time in Paris will be slightly behind schedule,
...which will now be 2:13 local time.
A search is underway for the two ringleaders, Benedetto and Gaspard Caderousse, who are wanted fugitives in all systems, and...
In Paris, it's 2 o'clock, huh?
Right this way, please.
Are you done paying your respects, then?
Yes.
Time certainly flies, doesn't it?
How many times will I have heard you play now? Five?
By the way, did you manage to meet your friend this year? Your... young gentleman?
Well, then, take your time.
Thank you, Father. I appreciate it.
Hi there, Franz.
I just got back.
As I said when we spoke over the phone,
I simply wasn't able to find a buyer.
As such, we will be taking the house to pay for the five years of accumulated back taxes.
Um... "The state hereby assumes all legal rights to this land and all structures thereupon,"
"...and will take over management of said land and structures".
You're sure that's all right with you?
Yes, sir. I have no objections.
In that case, please sign this form.
Um... Would it be all right if I went into the mansion one last time?
Of course. Feel free to go in while you're here.
If you don't mind...
Franz...
I've been frantic these past five years.
I read books like crazy, always hunched over my desk.
And before I knew it, I'd turned 20.
I was... I was simply frantic.
I told myself that I had to live.
That I had to live in your place, in Father's place, and in the Count's place.
Franz, I was terrified.
Of being trapped by the past.
That I might become obsessed with the past and end up hating someone.
I'm sorry, Franz...
I'm sorry it's been so long.
I'm sorry I haven't come back for so long.
Mademoiselle Mercedes Herrera.
It has been a long time.
How are you?
The ship has finally begun her return voyage to Earth.
Unfortunately, the Captain has fallen ill.
I don't think that it is anything serious, but it looks as if our return will be delayed.
To be honest, I wish I could come home right now and hold you in my arms.
That day we set sail, I could see the lights of Marseilles from the porthole as they receded into the distance.
A day doesn't go by when I don't think back on that warm light, the light of my loved ones.
Guided by that light, I never lose my way or stray from my path.
That light that is shining so brightly in our future is happiness.
So please wait for me and don't worry.
Instead of holding you in my arms now, I offer you these words:
Bide your time, and hold out hope.
To my beloved Mercedes.
With all my heart, your Edmond Dantes.
You've been here all this time...
Since long before I was born, haven't you?
I'll never forget the time I spent with you.
Or the time I spent with my father.
Or the time I spent with the Count.
I swear this to you.
No matter where my life takes me,
I'll never forget that summer.
Never.
Harsh words were said and lies were told instead
I didn't ever mean to make you cry
But love could make us weak and make us strong
And before too very long
I was totally in love with you, I bathed in you
Lost in you, captivated by you
Amazed by you, dazed by you
Nothing can go wrong
So tonight I'll sing a song to all my friends
Also to those we won't be seeing again
To those I knew and those I still adore
And I want to see once more
Debray (Domon Jin)
I just pray that you will love me and
Beauchamp (Shiratori Tetsu)
Trust me
Laugh with me and cry with me
Maximilien (Inada Tooru)
Valentine (Miura Junko)
Spend those silent times with me
Renaud (MIKI)
Love me ever more
Bertuccio (Ishii Kouji)
Baptistin (Tobita Nobuo)
Love me ever more
Peppo (Nakahara Mai)
You and I were lovers
Haidee (Yajima Akiko)
Our dreams were not soured by life
Eugenie (Nakamura Chie)
Franz (Hirakawa Daisuke)
And then my friends' betrayal
Fernand (Kosugi Juurouta)
Meant you never would be my wife
Mercedes (Inoue Kikuko)
Count of Monte Cristo (Nakata Jouji)
Harsh words were said and lies were told instead
I didn't ever mean to make you cry
But love could make us weak and make us strong
And before too very long
Albert (Fukuyama Jun)
I was totally in love with you, I bathed in you
Lost in you, captivated by you
Amazed by you, dazed by you
Nothing can go wrong