Ladies and gentlemen\ngood evening.
...my friend and I arrived in Paris\nwhere the boy awaited us.
I tremble in silence at these\nemotions which leak out...
...as the hour of reunion\ndraws near.
This must be\nyour guest.
Count if you don't mind I'd like you to join us\nfor dinner after you've met my parents.
Count?
If it is not\ntoo much trouble.
Please do. After all we owe you\nour son's life.
Welcome to our home
my good Count of Monte Cristo.
Act 4:
A Mother's Secrets
To our new friend the
Count of Monte Cristo.
Oh is that so?
I'm embarrassed that you
know of the Janina campaign.
The people praise me\nas a hero
...but to a soldier such\nthings mean little.
After all nothing good ever\nresults from destruction.
No these idyllic times in which we live\nwere built on the back of sacrifice.
Such is my opinion\nat any rate.
I expect that the far corners\nof the galaxy are echoing...
...with the name of
General Morcerf by now.
You honor me\nby saying so.
Oh dear the food wasn't\nto your liking?
Not at all. Please think\nnothing of it.
I am in the habit\nof eating very little.
I can't say that I don't\nunderstand how you feel.
Having advanced in years I find myself
weary of extravagant meals such as this.
In my case I find lately\nthat I seldom sleep either.
I'm amazed that you've managed\nto stay healthy.
It is because\nof these.
Are they some sort\nof space rations?
In the course of wandering the\nsea of stars for so long
...my body and soul have changed\nbeyond recognition.
Even so I hope that you
would at least eat something...
The thought of neither sleeping\nnor eating is too sad to bear.
Too sad to bear?
Very well then.
In that case perhaps
I shall sample this.
Please do.
This taste brings\nback memories...
Brings back memories?
I once experienced delightful cooking\nsuch as this in the south of France.
This is the dish that you've made for as\nlong as I can remember right Mother?
Yes.
By any chance you wouldn't happen\nto be from Marseilles would you?
No.
My wife has nothing to do
with such a barbaric province.
Isn't that right
Mercedes?
Y-Yes...
Oh really?
What's the matter?
One of my friends\nis from there.
His name is Maximilien Morrel.
He's a really nice person.
Morrel...
Forgive me if I misspoke.
Please do not take offense.
That's all right.
Our family traces its roots back\nto a powerful Catalan family.
This soup has been a specialty of my
wife's ever since she was a young girl.
Oh I see. So you and the Countess\nwere childhood friends then?
Yes that's right.
Which explains why you seem so close.
I am jealous beyond words.
I had no idea that a man like you could\nbe jealous of anyone Count.
Yes of course.
If that person is a man\nof your father's caliber.
Get the Count something to drink.
His glass is empty.
Please stay for as long\nas time permits.
Sitting around the table like this it almost\nfeels as if you are a member of the family.
What a maddening scent\nthis is...
Count?
It is from the\nmuscat grapes.
Are you fatigued?
No please forgive me for\nforcing you to eat earlier.
Not at all. I had always hoped to
experience that delicious flavor again.
It was a sublime\nexperience.
It was a simple\nrustic dish.
But it makes me happy\nto hear you say so.
Have you heard of this?
There is a saying that goes
"Those who share bread and salt under\nthe same roof become eternal friends."
That is a tradition handed down
in Eastern Space is it not?
Yes.
Which means that we are now friends.
For all eternity.
However this is not Eastern Space.
It is Paris.
In Paris everlasting friendship is impossible\nwithout the act of sharing bread and salt.
Your soup truly\nwas delicious.
Warm and yet evocative\nof past memories.
It is something\nwhich gives comfort.
Like a breeze blowing across\nthe Mediterranean Sea.
Count are you very familiar\nwith Marseilles?
I could say that
I am aware of it.
But perhaps I never truly\nknew it at all.
Infidelity. Adultery.
Dalliances in the dead of night.
You aristocrats are as energetic\nas the rumors say.
Spare me your\ncrude comments!
The Count is a friend\nof mine.
Honestly you're such\na child.
If people could become friends simply\nby sharing bread and salt
...life would be simpler.
What are you\ntalking about?
You'll understand sooner\nor later little boy.
I am most grateful to you for allowing me\nto experience a day such as today.
Not at all. I'm proud that I had the
opportunity to introduce you to my parents.
To introduce a\nman I admire.
What say you?
I would like to invite you to my residence\non the Champs-Elysees in the near future.
I'd love to come!
The Count of Monte Cristo was a
mysterious man don't you think?
Yes. There was a sternness somewhere\nin him that keeps people at arm's length.
That just means that compared to the Count\nthe people of Paris are dull.
My...
You might not know this Mother but\nthere's more to the world than Paris.
Out beyond the walls there's a world\nthat's endlessly captivating.
I think you've changed\nsince your journey to Luna.
My journey is\njust beginning.
Don't go to worlds too far\nremoved from our own.
You should exercise moderation\nin your association with the Count.
Oh please Mother...
You sound just like Franz.
Well even though he seems\nmore than a little shady
...having the Morcerf family establish ties with\na man like him might not be a bad thing.
Not when this family is about to
throw its hat into the political arena.
Good grief why do aristocrats
eat like this all the time?
Dinner parties high tea\nballs...
It's probably because they
don't have anything else to do.
In other words if you took away\nthe gluttony lust and avarice
...there wouldn't be\nanything left.
You need to watch\nyour mouth.
Didn't you think that their guest today\nwas rather elegant and handsome?
I'm not so sure.
He wasn't very refined.
Maybe but he had a pretty good vibe going\nwith the mistress under the grapevine trellis.
What really? I'd always thought that the master\nwas the only man in the world for the mistress.
I think that any society lady would fall for\nthat Count if he worked his mojo on her.
Give it a rest already!
That was definitely the face\nof a woman in love.
If you don't stop that
I'm going to report you.
Oo I'm so scared...
That's preposterous. Mother is the last person\nin the world who would be capable of...
Mother?
Who's in that picture\nshe's looking at?
Do you find me\na horrible man?
No. I will stay at your side\nfor as long as I live.
Even if that means walking down\nthe path to ruin.
It is not we\nwho will be ruined.
I have come home
Father.
What you're still here?
Hey don't touch those!
I hate to break it to you but I've gotten\ninto your father's good graces
...so I'll be staying here\nfor a while.
His "good graces"?
It means that your father\nis a man like any other.
Give those bad jokes\na rest.
Well setting aside your\nfather for the moment
...the one that I'd be worried about\nis your mother you know?
What's that supposed\nto mean?
I mean she was staring so wistfully\nat that picture of a young man...
You saw that?
It was definitely\na picture of a man.
A man who wasn't\nyour father.
Oh I can understand.
If my mother was staring at a\npicture of some strange man
...l'd be depressed too.
That's about enough!
Get out!
Yes sir!
Eugenie? I didn't know\nyou were here.
Ever the late riser
I see.
Why are you dressed\nlike that?
What's wrong\nwith it?
Skirts just don't work\non you.
I didn't come here\nto see you Albert!
Then don't have me dragged\nout of bed!
I'm the one who had you\nwoken up Albert.
Is something\nthe matter?
No ma'am.
Eugenie is your fiancee\nisn't she?
I think it's only natural that you\nshould greet her when she's over.
Sure I suppose.
Um are you going somewhere?
Oh we're just going out to do\na little shopping together.
Let's go Madame!
Of course.
That reminds me. What's this I hear about the
Count of Monte Cristo inviting you over?
How did you\nknow that?
I heard about it\nfrom Franz.
He said that he and Maximilien\nwere also invited.
They were invited too?
What's he...
Peppo!
What are you doing?
Oh hi Albert!
Don't you "Oh hi!" me!
Don't play around with Mother's jewelry!
But they're so pretty!
If my father sees you like that
there'll be hell to pay!
Fine fine.
I'll put them back then.
You're dying to know
what's in there aren't you?
It's like your mother's secret
treasure is hidden inside.
Impossible.
Oh there's no such thing as a human being\nwho doesn't have secrets.
Just like you and I share\na certain secret night.
That only happened because
I was tricked by you!
If you ever want that lock opened\ncome tell me anytime.
I specialize in getting\ninto people's drawers.
Stop being crude\nand get back to work!
Oh. Fine.
It can't be...
Why would Mother have\na picture of the Count?
This is ridiculous.
What am I so worried about?
His Excellency General Morcerf!
Ten-hut!
All high and mighty...
How do I look?
Not too strange I hope?
It looks wonderful\non you.
What?
Thank goodness.
You're more upbeat than I expected.
Gee thanks.
For a visit to the Count's place that outfit isn't\nquite flamboyant enough don't you think?
Not flamboyant enough?
Albert? What in the world\nare you wearing?
What's wrong\nwith it?
Where do I\neven begin?
I'll never understand the ways\nof you aristocrats.
Why are you dressed\nlike a pirate?!
Uh what are you even\ndoing here Beauchamp?
You don't expect me to miss my chance to\nget photos of the Count's mansion do you?
Oh brother. And here I had hoped to go\nthere by myself if at all possible.
That day when I first met you you made me\nrealize that there is always hope
...regardless of the circumstances\nyou might find yourself in.
I will never forget\nthat lesson.
Hope...
When I was flung out of the Chateau d'lf\ninto the black void of space
...hope was the one thing\nthat I had in my possession.
You're sure\nthis is it?
Yep. number thirty Champs-Elysees.
No doubt about it.
It's a lot more austere than I expected\nit to be considering the Count.
I was expecting the sort of place that would\ndrive a commoner into a rage if he saw it.
Welcome messieurs.
We have been expecting you.
Early Rococo huh?
And not Revival either.
Isn't this amazing?
Well it's a bit too far removed\nfrom my world...
Please pardon the delay.
Allow me to show you to the Count.
What the...?
We're going down!
Baptistin where are\nwe going?
We've stopped!
Welcome messieurs.
The Count awaits.
That's...
Even the floor and columns are gold...
The man has expensive tastes.
Where could he have gotten\nthis much gold?
That's why I think there's\nsomething fishy about him.
At this rate I bet his bed and
pillows are gonna be solid gold too.
I'd never be able to fall asleep\nwith all this glare.
Hey! Look at that!
That's...
The sea?
No wait.
Look at that sky!
It's artificial?
I can't believe it...
This alone would make\none hell of a story.
This is so beautiful...
Wait I know\nthis view!
That look suits you quite well\nSir Pirate.
Count!
Wha...?
If you don't mind I would like
you to have this Sir Pirate.
I was given this blade by a\ncertain ship's navigator.
Perhaps it will serve to protect you\nas well as to carve a path for you.
When we meet someone
...the selfless considerate part of us\nclashes with the selfish love of our emotions.
Next time on Gankutsuou
The Count of Monte Cristo act 5
Act 5:
Do You Love Your Fiancee?
..."Do You Love Your Fiancee?"
Bide your time\nand hold out hope!