Ladies and gentlemen,
good evening.
When he learned something
of his mother's past,
...the young man saw in her profile
the figure of a woman.
However, he is
still unaware.
Still unaware of the true identity of the man
who brought this look to her face.
Act 5:
Do You Love Your Fiancée?
I can't believe I'm seeing sights like this
underneath the Champs Elysees.
It's like a dream.
Perhaps this truly is
but a dream.
At times, I find myself forced
to consider that possibility.
In that case, here's an eye-opening question
for you. How much did you sink into this?
How much did this dream house
of yours set you back?
We stopped bothering with hassles
like keeping track of the money...
...halfway through construction.
Thanks for that reply.
It'll make a great headline.
Where's that music
coming from?
There!
She's the girl from
the opera!
She's beautiful...
You're not gonna try and tell us
that she's artificial, too, are you?
Don't be rude!
She's...
She is a doll
named Haidee.
A poor puppet who still lives, even
after her soul has been stolen away.
Haidee obeys
my every whim,
...and should I wish it, would not
hesitate to take her own life.
You're kidding...
Don't be so surprised. This is the Count
of Monte Cristo we're talking about.
He renounced his soul
ages ago.
Am I wrong?
You're going too far,
Beauchamp!
How else could a man amass a fortune
like this in one lifetime?
I'm afraid... I must agree.
Why are you all
acting like this?
Listen, the Count isn't as cold
a man as you think he is.
Isn't that right,
Count?
I would not know.
I cannot see myself.
Welcome to our home.
I am Haidee.
H-Hello.
Who's that?
He is Ali. Like Haidee, he is
a noble doll that I own.
Haidee, the Viscount
seems perplexed...
...as to what
you are to me.
I am but a humble twig
that allows the Count to bloom.
A graceful girl like her is the twig,
and the Count is the flower, huh?
Are you happy
like this?
I know the joy of making
the flowers bloom.
But...
Does my harp's music
sound gloomy?
No.
The notes of a harp
are the notes of the heart.
The strings don't respond
to a hesitant, timid heart,
...and a tense heart will cause
the strings to break.
Being with the Count
makes me happy.
I assumed that you and the Count
were in love with one another...
In love with each other, huh?
Could you be any more naive?
What's that supposed
to mean?
Think about it.
Marriage among aristocrats is just a strategic
alliance with the goal of cementing fortunes.
In point of fact, that's why Franz
and Valentine are engaged, right?
Is that true?!
Well, I won't deny it...
Right, Albert? Isn't it the same
with you and Eugenie?
Well, I guess...
In other words, love is something that
doesn't exist in the privileged class.
How can this be...
What's the matter,
Maximilien?
Is what I said too hard
to swallow?
No.
Even so, everything I said
was the truth.
The only thing that's important to them is
keeping their family fortune from shrinking.
In other words, you two aren't the product of
love, you're the product of financial interests.
I wouldn't be so sure.
For my parents at least, they say that
their marriage was out of love.
I find that hard to believe. A notorious
player like General Morcerf?
Are you trying to
insult my father?!
Seeing you get so mad about it
makes it seem even more dubious.
Is there something about your parents
that you're feeling guilty about?
Of course not.
Why would I feel guilty
about anything?
Hey, Beauchamp.
I don't care if you think you're a journalist.
You should drop this subject.
Hey, what's this? You're clamping
down on freedom of speech now?
"How wretched it all is..."
Is that not what you are thinking,
...my good
Captain Morrel?
To think that loveless marriages
are allowed to go unquestioned...
Is something wrong,
Maximilien?
The people of Paris
are corrupt!
Maximilien, you're going too far!!
I demand that you take that back!
I can't do that.
Paris has more than its fair share of honest,
upright people! Take back what you said!
I can't do that.
Take it back!
I can't.
Stop it, Albert!
Hey, now...
Stop it.
Viscount Morcerf.
Do you realize what you
are pointing at me?
I must warn you,
I am a soldier.
This will not do.
It is unseemly for one party to draw
his sword while the other does not.
Count?
It appears to me that each of you
is steadfast in your opinion.
As we are at sea, perhaps we pirates
should act the part...
...and have a duel?
A duel?
On the sea, strength counts
for everything.
He with the better sword arm
makes the rules.
Are you serious?
What are you suggesting, Count?!
Come, now is the time to
demonstrate your conviction.
Prove to them that you hold your
parents' marriage to be sacred.
The blade in your hand
is invincible.
And you, Monsieur?
All men have a blade
in their heart.
The purer the heart,
the keener the blade.
The time is high tide, the place is the ship's
bow, and the weapons are bare blades!
Come on, gentlemen!
Let's see you go at it,
pirate style!
It's hard to believe that there are still people in
this day and age who'd fight a duel over love...
Is this any time to be joking?!
Those swords are real!
And the water down there is teeming with
sharks that are thirsting for human blood!
Count, what are you
trying to do?!
Sea voyages are accompanied
by their own entertainment.
I expect that Monsieur Albert is
thirsting for stimulation of this sort.
Let's do it!
Whenever you're ready.
Take back
what you said!
I can't!
Why, you...!
How about now?!
You poor, sad people...
The purer the heart,
the keener the blade.
You aren't capable
of defeating me.
Shut up!
Understand this.
No matter what you say, no matter
how it is with other families,
...my parents' marriage
is a sacred bond!
I didn't expect you to turn
towards your unarmed side.
I admire your agility.
Nevertheless, the insincere will be
smitten by righteous anger!
I won't stand for it!
I won't!
What in the world's gotten
into Maximilien?
I guess he's the
scrupulous type.
You're finished!
Why do you have such disdain
for the aristocracy?!
That's none of
your concern!
The hell it isn't!
Tell me why!
In that case, there's something
I want to ask you, too!
Is it true that you don't
love your fiancée?
Well, l...
I demand an answer!
I don't know!
As I thought, I can't
abide by this!
You have lost, Monsieur.
Hey, hold it!
Albert!
- Albert!
- Don't!
There are sharks
down there!
This is a nightmare...
Indeed it is.
This is a dream.
All is but a waking dream.
Albert...
Mother...
I did it because you had that
look on your face, Mother...
Count...
One cannot fight destiny.
I'm ashamed of myself.
I can't believe how angry I got.
I can see it clearly.
Within your heart, another side
of yourself lies dormant.
At the moment, you are burdened with
a profound sense of apprehension.
As am I.
You are, Count?
I have need of you.
Who, me?
You and I met
that day on Luna.
Perhaps you feel that our meeting
was a chance encounter.
But in fate, there are
no coincidences.
Just as that setting sun does so
according to the laws of the universe,
...fate, too, is composed
of unyielding necessity.
What are you apprehensive
about, Count?
It is because a man loves
that he laughs, cries, and hates.
Count, what are you saying?
My life is much like
this miniature garden.
It is a hollow,
fragile thing.
C'mon, Albert, cheer up already.
Maximilien already apologized, didn't he?
I'm not mad.
Then why...
Don't hang around
the Count anymore.
You've been acting
funny lately.
You're right.
I guess I have.
Something's funny.
Something about all this.
Up until yesterday, life was one
uneventful day after another.
It almost feels like something hidden
is at work behind all this.
Destiny... Have you ever thought
about fate and stuff like that?
No. I don't believe
in that stuff.
How did your mother
and I meet?
Why the sudden interest?
Please, I'd like to know.
As I've told you before, your mother and I
were married after a storybook courtship.
Yes, it was just as your father says.
We were lovers.
I've never seen that look
on Mother's face before.
You look like you're delirious
with a fever, young master.
Why don't you go out
for some fresh air?
Make sure you
clean in here!
Yes, sir!
Mother, who are you thinking
about right now?
How far will the ship sail,
I wonder?
There is no
turning back now.
I see... You hope to expand your business
ventures to include Paris, as well?
I can think of no stronger backer to
have than yourself, General Morcerf.
You do me a great honor,
Monte Cristo.
I take it that you already
have a plan of action.
Please feel free to call on me
should you have any need at all.
He seems to be
quite powerful.
The crest of the Danglars family can
be seen here and there around town.
He has no idea that the Count
is keeping a close eye on him.
Talk about conceited.
Waving a sword around
in anger like that...
You really are hopeless,
you know that?
Tell me, what kind of relationship
do you and I have?
What brought this on?
Something that
Maximilien said.
"Is it true that you don't
love your fiancée?"
Oh.
Do you, Albert?
You and I... are childhood
friends, right?
You and Franz
have changed.
In the old days, the three of us
would always have fun together.
But now, the two of you sneak off
on trips by yourselves...
Everybody is changing.
Do you know why Maximilien
was so angry?
You honestly don't know?
Well, if you say so.
What's that supposed
to mean?!
I guess no one can do anything
to stop it...
...when two people have feelings
for each other.
I didn't mean to keep
you waiting, Eugenie.
I'm sorry. It took a long time
to get ready.
That's all right.
Oh, my. Albert, is something the matter?
You look so grim.
Stay safe.
Hey! Albert!
Albert!
She and her father.
And her mother.
The specter of uncertainty sneaks up on
them through their conflicting emotions.
Next time on Gankutsuou,
The Count of Monte Cristo, Act 6:
Act 6:
Her Melancholy, My Melancholy
..."Her Melancholy,
My Melancholy."
Bide your time,
and hold out hope!