When he steals into a mansion with a friend
in order to help him win over his love,
...the young man witnesses a physical
liaison between two adults.
My friend said to me,
"He must know."
"Until the day his innocent soul
is destroyed."
Act 8:
A Night in Boulogne
This is bad...
Albert!
W-What are you
barging in here for?!
I'm sorry. I kept calling,
but you didn't answer.
You have a visitor from
the Champs Elysees.
The Count?
His Excellency says that he does
not wish to see you today.
Did he give you a message
or something?
No, Monsieur, nothing
in particular.
I see...
What's this?
His Excellency wishes
to unveil his new villa.
That is an invitation to a dinner party.
By all means, bring your entire family.
With pleasure!
Where is the villa?
The forest of Auteuil.
He has a villa in
that gloomy place?
Yes. His Excellency insisted
on this villa in particular.
If I'm not mistaken, Monsieur Villefort
used to own this villa.
It's almost fallen
to ruin.
While his first wife was still alive,
it was a bright, cheerful place.
You mean Valentine's
real mother?
She was still so young and
beautiful when she died.
Thank you for coming.
My lord General.
Thank you for
inviting us.
Count!
Well, well! The good
Madame Villefort!
This is my husband, the...
The Crown Prosecutor,
I presume?
I'm told that you did a great
service for my wife and son.
I am honored that you have gone
to all the trouble of coming here.
This manor is a little too dreary to
invite guests over, don't you think?
Not at all, I have taken quite
a liking to the silence here.
Now, I see that the three gentlemen who
embody Paris are gathered here tonight.
Monsieur Danglars,
the king of bankers.
General Morcerf, who commands
the military.
And you, Monsieur, who
administers the law.
There is a reason that I invited you here
to this humble affair tonight.
Allow me to be frank and
make a confession to you.
Travelers are insecure
by their very nature.
I would like to forge bonds of friendship
with you three gentlemen.
I am given to understand that you hope
to win the presidency, General.
Where did you
hear that?!
I would like to assist you to the best
of my humble abilities.
Albert. Leave us
for a moment.
What? But l...
We adults need to have
a discussion.
Albert, what's the matter?
You look a little out of it.
You don't look well.
No, I'm fine, Mother.
I'm sorry I forced you
to come.
I wonder if the Count
is avoiding me...
At Valentine's house,
I saw something.
I saw the Count and Madame Villefort
being... intimate.
So?
While I was watching,
the Count spotted me.
It seemed that way
to me, anyway.
What about it?
I'm a terrible person...
I guess the Count has
a lot on his plate.
It just means that he's
a man like any other.
Anyway, weren't you supposed to go there to
work out the whole Maximilien situation?
That's the least of my
worries right now.
Um...
Would it be all right
if I joined you?
Who is this?
I'm going outside for
some fresh air.
Um, might l...
What the hell
did you do?
And who might
you be, boy?
M-Me, sir? I am...
This is Captain Maximilien Morrel,
a most capable soldier.
How do you do, sir?
I'm Captain Maximilien Morrel,
Canes Venatici Gamma Army.
My family operates a trading
firm in Marseilles. As for me, l...
And what do you want?
Sir. I-I would like to ask for
your daughter's hand in...
Yours is a noble profession,
one which defends the state.
For that, I offer you
my respects.
Nevertheless, you are
a simple commoner.
And my daughter
is already engaged.
I suggest that you bear
those facts in mind.
How rude!
Bouillabaisse à la Marseilles.
So, how did the marriage
proposal go?
Dead on arrival.
You know, maybe she really
has feelings for you.
And what's this secret
conversation about?
Beauchamp!
You've got guts, firing off a flash
at the Crown Prosecutor like that.
When I see a guy who's full of himself,
my rebellious streak takes over.
So, what's up?
The sorrows of youth?
Geez, what a sad world we're living in.
It's all "love" this and "affairs" that.
Look at that.
Rumor has it that those two were
having an affair years ago, too.
The Crown Prosecutor
and Eugenie's mother used to...
Forgive me for imposing
on you.
It's all right.
Don't worry about it.
I've paid a small fortune
for her lessons.
It's only fair that she should put it
to good use at times like this.
Please listen to what
I have to say.
I'd like to apologize
to you.
What I said the other day was terrible.
I didn't give any thought to your feelings.
What did Valentine say?
She was crying.
I guess I made you do my
dirty work for me. I'm sorry.
Valentine loves you.
You're kidding!
She does!
I'm sure of it.
Eugenie's gotten really good,
hasn't she?
Hey, don't try to change
the subject.
I talked to her
the other day.
I bet she had a lot of bad things
to say about me.
Pretty much.
What's that mean?
Tell me! C'mon, tell me!
What do you want from me
after all this time?
I'm frightened.
What if someone
sees us?
But when we're here, I can't help
but think of our child!
Magnificent.
I see that music is truly
your calling.
Her calling, huh? The Count must
know a lot of talented people.
Thank you for the lovely performance,
my lovely lady.
How do you do?
Now that one talented youth has made her
debut, allow me to introduce another.
This is Marquis Andrea Cavalcanti.
Oh, my...
That family had
an heir?
His father is an old friend
of mine.
If you would welcome him as you have done
me, nothing would make me happier.
I realize that I am an untested youth who only
recently inherited his late father's estate,
...but I am honored to
make your acquaintance.
Look at that brooch!
It easily cost five million!
Who's that guy?
The Count's new favorite, I'd say.
I bet he has all kinds
of talents!
Well, ladies
and gentlemen.
I do hate to interrupt your conversation,
but if I might have your attention please?
One of the reasons that I
purchased this estate...
...was that I wished to escape from the noise of
the city and spend time in quiet contemplation.
But on the contrary,
once I arrived here,
...I found myself fascinated by a certain
aura that pervades this old mansion.
And what might
that be?
How might one
best describe it?
Yes... In a word...
...a curse.
I found myself pondering
certain questions.
What sorts of lives were led by
the people who once lived here?
And what sad events occured here that
were hidden away from the eyes of all?
When my mind toys with such thoughts, I am
filled with inexpressible joy and tranquility.
No doubt about it...
It's him,
I'm sure of it...
Preposterous!
A curse, the very idea...
Monsieur Prosecutor, you suggest
that you do not sense...
...the gloomy, malevolent aura
that pervades this mansion?
That's CROWN Prosecutor.
Very well. I take it, then, that you must
see it with your own two eyes.
In truth, there is one room deep inside
this mansion that has been left exactly as it was.
Why would you do that?
I am convinced that
it is that room...
...which is the source of the
malevolent aura here.
How rude!
We're leaving.
Monsieur!
Now, now, now, don't be
like that!
I for one say that we should indulge
our host's eccentricities.
What do you say, everyone? Why don't we
go see this "evil room" for ourselves?
Just a moment, please!
Going all at once would
spoil the entertainment.
Monsieur Albert!
Yes?
Monsieur Franz!
And Mademoiselle Eugenie.
Me?
I suggest that you split into three groups
to search for the room.
We shall have these three youths
lead the way.
I will offer a small gift to those
who successfully reach...
...the innermost depths
of this dark mansion.
Are we agreed?
I like it!
This sounds like fun!
By all means,
let's do it!
Monsieur Albert, if you
would be so kind?
Yes, sir!
It's been a long time,
Marquise.
You're looking well.
Keep your mind
on the task at hand.
As they say, it's the early bird
that gets the worm.
Incidentally, Marquis Andrea,
where are you from?
Oh. Excuse me. I come from the
far reaches of the eastern galaxy.
There is a beautiful planetary
cluster there.
And on one of those planets
can be found a bird...
...which eats ore and lays
eggs of jewels.
Once every 50 years, they build a colony
for the purpose of mating, and...
We can finally speak
privately now.
Pardon me.
Count. I need to say
something to you.
Whatever is the matter,
Madame Morcerf?
Please, call me Mercedes.
This heart of the malevolent aura
that he mentioned...
What do you suppose
its heart really is?
Why are you so fixated
on Marseilles?
Whatever do you mean?
You served another dish from Marseilles
for dinner tonight.
Was it not to your liking?
No. It's just that when I look at you,
I am reminded of someone I once knew.
For many years, I have lived with
the desire to see him once again.
But now, I'm filled with
a terrible foreboding...
Count?
You are not alone. Never.
There is someone who
is always thinking of you.
Please don't forget that.
This is my good luck charm. It was
given to me by my late father.
I'd like you
to have it.
It's a dead end...
I've had enough of this, Albert.
Madame Danglars is tired, too.
We're turning back.
Monsieur Villefort!
There's a door inside!
T-This is...
Congratulations to you.
Your party is the first
to arrive.
Did you enjoy the unique ambiance
that this mansion has to offer?
I see that the master of this house doesn't
know the proper way to entertain guests!
Monsieur Albert, might I
ask for your assistance?
Yes, sir!
Thank you for playing along.
It must have been difficult.
I'm sorry, Count.
Sorry? Whatever for?
The truth is, I... I saw you.
In Madame Villefort's greenhouse.
Goodness, how awkward.
You saw us, did you?
Madame would not take no
for an answer, you see.
I simply assumed that you
were angry with me!
Perish the thought!
Incidentally, it is I who
should apologize to you.
I have been unable to speak
with you properly until today.
The fact of the matter is that I suffer from
an illness I contracted in distant space.
From time to time, I wish to
rest without seeing anyone.
That's...
It is nothing serious. I do feel a
numbness from time to time, however.
Albert. This is a secret
known only to you and me.
A secret between
you and me.
I understand.
I give you my word.
In that case, let us carry
this box through the door.
This is the room where
I gave birth to the child!
The child... The child has
summoned us here!
Pull yourself together!
But on that night
17 years ago...
Congratulations! This is our gift
from the Count!
NO!
Madame?
You...
Who the devil
are you?!
A poisonous evil stalks
the lovers.
But I am still unaware that I am about
to fall prey to it, as well.
Next time on Gankutsuou,
The Count of Monte Cristo, Act 9:
Act 9:
I Dreamed a Dark Dream
..."I Dreamed
a Dark Dream."
Bide your time,
and hold out hope!