Ladies and gentlemen\ngood evening.
My friend said to me "This shall be\nthe prelude to my vengeance."
But this soul was too young\nand beautiful.
It is that alone which\ngives me cause for fear.
Act 2:
Until the Sun Rises Over the Moon
Are you going to come?
That's enough\nfun and games boy.
I heard you met him\nthe other day.
Are you bored?
Not at all. It's a wonderful party\ndon't you think?
Where is your friend?
Oh you mean Albert?
He's probably out trying to pick up girls and\ngetting turned down by every one of them.
But this is terrible!
This is Luna!
Strolling around alone at
night is tantamount to suicide!
Surely you're exaggerating...
It's no laughing matter.
You'll get kidnapped by Luigi Vampa!
Luigi Vampa?
He's an up-and-coming\nbandit!
They say that he drags his victims\ninto the catacombs
...tortures them\nand finally kills them!
How horrible!
Surely the police won't\nstand by and do nothing.
You don't know?
The police on Luna arrange\ntheir patrols to avoid the bandits.
My very own cousin was robbed blind\nhad his arms and legs broken
...and was left stark naked\nin the plaza!
All because he spoke\nto the bandit's mistress!
I'm sure he's fine. I bet that he's back\nat your hotel at this very moment.
Would you care\nto dance?
I simply despise when\na party ends.
First one guest leaves then two.
Especially at this hour.
You won't abandon me\nwill you?
Take him away.
You can't! It's mean!
Today is my birthday!
I'm sorry Franz.
I have to go.
No no no!
Your father is leaving to see to\nsome very important business.
Fine see if I care! I hope\nyou never come back!
Father...
Oh I'm sorry.
Did I keep you waiting long?
I... think I should go.
Are you Baron
Franz d'Epinay?
Hey you're that...
I'm sick of\nyour whining!
As for me I killed\nten people!
This is for you.
"My Lord Baron
Franz d'Epinay."
"I Luigi Vampa have taken custody of\nyour friend the Viscount Albert Morcerf."
"Hand over the sum of 50 million ducats\nto my messenger immediately."
"If the messenger should\nnot return by sunrise
"...although it pains me to do so\nthink of your friend's life as forfeit."
Where is Albert?!
He's a valuable hostage so we're\ntaking real good care of him.
If the money is handed over he'll be sent\nhome without so much as a scratch.
You should have died!
Is this how you people do things?
Even I have a certain\nlifestyle to maintain.
50 million\nis absurd!
I'm sure that a Parisian aristocrat won't be\nhard pressed to come up with such a sum.
Dawn comes fast\non Luna.
If you value your\nfriend's life
...I suggest that you make arrangements\nfor the money as soon as possible.
I want to make an immediate withdrawal\nfrom the Bank of Paris!
I'm terribly sorry\nsir
...but our connection to Europe is currently\noffline due to solar winds.
Isn't there anything\nyou can do?!
How much does\nsir require?
Albert... Damn!
Say son it's awfully sad to see a young fella like\nyourself all alone on the last night of Carnival.
If you want I know\na fine girl who...
Please just be quiet\nand drive.
It was at my father's funeral\nthat I first met Albert...
Don't cry.
I'm not crying...
I'll play with you\nso cheer up.
Leave me alone!
Get lost!
Hey...
Ever since that day Albert
and I have been inseparable.
Damn! What am I\ngoing to do?
It's almost sunrise!
Have you raised\nthe money yet?
Give me more time!
Once it's morning I'll have the\nmoney transferred from Paris!
I'm sorry Luigi is a stickler\nfor punctuality.
If you don't have the money ready by sunrise\nyour friend is a goner.
Stop messing\nwith me!
I suggest that\nyou hurry.
I'm sure that you don't want to see your\nfriend die a horrible death My Lord Baron.
You bastard!
Violence is unseemly
My Lord Baron.
Damn it!
Yeah that's better. A gentleman has
to worry about little things like discretion.
There is no more fascinating spectacle\nthan a man's death.
Yes it almost feels as if one has\nbecome God does it not?
His Excellency\nthe Baron d'Epinay.
I'm sorry to disturb you\nat such an hour...
Is something the matter?
You do not seem entirely well.
Count! I have a favor\nto ask of you!
What's the big idea?!
There is your
50 million ducats.
Now you will take us\nto the hostage.
To the Colosseum!
Have the two of you been\nfriends for a long time?
Yes we've been best friends\nsince we were children.
Ah so you are\nchildhood friends.
Constant friendship...
It is a wonderful thing\nis it not?
Who do you like?
C'mon tell me!
At least give me\na hint!
You wouldn't understand.
Luigi.
It's almost time.
Kill him.
So have you made\nyour peace?
C'mon ma'am\nlet me kill him!
No let me!
Oh give it a rest\nyou two!
You can carve him up as much
as you want after he's dead.
Now then. You should put up\na brave front while you still can.
I wonder what you'll sound like\nwhen you cry?
H-Hey guys.
Um... Visitors to\nsee the boss.
Who are they?
Please Teresa don't!
We can't kill him yet!
B-Because we won't get\nthe money!
And besides... There's still\na little time.
Stand aside!
If you're going to use that\nuse it on me!
Squabbling among yourselves\nis pathetic!
Thank you.
Stand back.
Are you trying to disgrace\nthe boss?
I'll be fine. Go.
So does that mean\nyou've fallen for that girl?
That's so sweet...
But she's too much for you\nto handle little boy.
Or maybe... you'd rather become\none of us?
You know I think I'll brand you...
Why you...
Leave her alone!
I have come to meet with Signor Luigi Vampa\nwhose reputation is notorious on Luna.
And who are you?
My name is... Gankutsuou.
T-The King\nof the Cave?!
For one such as yourself who\ndwells in the darkness
...I expect that I am better\nknown by that name.
I have your money.
Now hand over the hostage.
I'm sorry but you missed\nthe deadline.
"Always be punctual"\nthat's my motto.
"Punctuality is the politeness\nof kings" is that it?
I'm deeply honored... by your\ngracious words!
I see... Your skill\nis impressive.
But you cannot kill me.
A-Are you...
Are you really...
A-Are you really him?!
I do not work for\nthe authorities.
If you would do me the honor\nof returning my friend
...all will be well.
You aren't injured I take it?
I had a feeling that you\nwould come to rescue me.
If you wish to thank someone
thank the good Baron d'Epinay.
He was gravely concerned\nfor your wellbeing.
Hey! Miss!
Are you okay?
Say I never asked you\nwhat your name was...
I'm Albert.
Albert de Morcerf.
I'm Peppo.
To tell you the truth I was almost considering\nthrowing in my lot with the bandits.
I'm glad you're all right Albert.
What took you\nso long Franz?
I came this close to being killed\nyou know!
I was seriously...
What was that for?
Please do not concern yourselves\nover the matter.
It served as a pleasant\ndiversion for me.
But I have to do something\nto repay you.
In that case might I ask\none favor of you?
Anything at all!
Just name it!
I should like to take up
residence in Paris at some point.
That's wonderful!
However a rustic aristocrat such as myself\nhas no connections in Paris.
As such might I impose on you to act as\nmy intermediary into Parisian society?
Think nothing of it!
In that case I shall call on you on
May 22nd three months from this day
...to commemorate the\nevents of this day.
Where in the world\ndid you find this?
I found it.
At the opera house.
Oh so that is\nwhere it was!
It shames me to say it
but I have looked everywhere for it.
This too shows that there\nis some bond between us.
Please accept it\nwith my gratitude.
Think of it as a small token\nof our friendship.
Really?
It will serve to freeze the memory\nof this day this hour in time.
A memory which belongs\nto us alone.
Thank you so much!
I'll cherish it!
Carnival has ended so what\nare your plans now?
We're going to cut our trip short and\ntake the evening shuttle back to Paris.
Hey wait a minute!
I've already made plans of my own!
You never learn do you?
And what "plans" might these be?
What do you mean?
It's none of your business.
Have you arranged\na rendezvous perhaps?
Sort of...
Love is a\nwonderful thing.
However perhaps you\nhave not noticed yet.
Or perhaps you knew and
arranged the rendezvous regardless.
I do hate to be the bearer\nof bad tidings but...
A boy?
She's a boy?!
Come out and say it! You think
I'm an idiot don't you?!
Not really.
You're always looking down on me\nlaughing at me on the inside!
I'm not laughing\nat you!
If I laughed at every boneheaded stunt\nyou pulled I'd bust a gut!
Anyway you were...
Thanks.
I owe you my life.
I appreciate it.
The fruits of betrayal must
be plucked from the tree...
At long last the appointed day arrives.
He comes to Paris along with a summer storm.
Next time on Gankutsuou
The Count of Monte Cristo act 3
Act 3:
5/22 Stormy
..."5/22 Stormy".
Bide your time\nand hold out hope!