I was reunited with the young man
at my friend's residence.
His soul, which does not know
what it means to love another,
...was profoundly shaken by one
who does know what it is to love.
He asked, "Do you love
your fiancée?"
My life is a hollow,
fragile thing.
I think we should give some more
thought to my marriage to Eugenie.
What brought this on?
I'm just not sure if I really
love her or not.
Pull!
That's what's been
bothering you?
First you go through the motions.
Then the emotions will follow.
Pull!
Monsieur Albert, a messenger from the
Count of Monte Cristo said to deliver this to you.
From the Count?
Invitations to the opera...
"As luck would have it, I managed to secure
an open box at the opera house."
"If you like, would you care
to join me this evening?"
"By all means, please bring
your fiancée."
I can't imagine how there could be
any open boxes at the opera house...
You're right.
I'm sorry, but could you
deliver this to Eugenie?
Albert, you're going
to deliver it.
Father?
Considerate little touches like
this will win her over little by little.
Pull!
Act 6:
Her Melancholy, My Melancholy
Don't wake her
this morning.
Is Monsieur Debray here?
Here comes Mademoiselle!
Good morning, Mademoiselle.
Good morning.
Is Mother still sleeping?
Yes, Mademoiselle,
it looks that way.
Good morning, Eugenie.
You're as lovely as ever.
Good morning.
You spent the night, I see.
Father, your soup
is getting cold.
Yes, of course...
Good morning, Baron.
Hello. I trust you
slept well last night?
Yes, sir. Thank you for
your hospitality.
By the way,
about Olympus Trading...
I'm sure of it.
That's a valuable piece of information... Thank you!
I give appropriate compensation to those
who give me information before anyone else.
If you're not in a hurry, would you care
to join us for breakfast?
Thank you for
the invitation.
I was on my way to give
Eugenie her ticket.
I am on my way to visit Baron Danglars
to see to some business negotiations.
What a lucky coincidence!
Please, allow me to introduce you to them!
This is indeed an unexpected
stroke of good luck.
There are many things at their estate
that you will find interesting.
That reminds me, if you have time, you should
ask them to show you the stables.
Madame Danglars has a horse named Eclipse
that is the finest in all of Paris.
This way, Messieurs. If you will wait
in the parlor for a moment...
Albert!
Lucien! What brings you here
so early in the morning?
Oh, I had my hands full
with this and that.
Eugenie!
Good morning!
A man has to play
his cards right.
Right?
Count! Do me the honor of allowing me
to invite you to my home next time.
Of course. Gladly.
That reminds me,
I'll stop by your room later!
Michelle, Olympus Trading
has started to fall.
We'll pretend to prop it up,
and then make it fall even farther!
Further buying is inadvisable.
It is below the insolvency line.
I don't care. Wait until it hits bottom,
and then buy them out.
Understood.
A few hundred investors are gonna
hang themselves over this.
Monsieur, the Count of Monte Cristo
is waiting in the parlor.
He is, eh?
Michelle, have the credit
assessment results...
...for this Count of Monte Cristo
person come in yet?
Out of three investigatory agencies,
two rate him as AA+,
...and the third rates him
as AAA.
His peerage title is valid,
as well.
I bet. He probably paid a lot
of money for it.
I'm terribly sorry to
keep you waiting.
Oh, you're here,
too, Albert?
Good morning, Baron.
This is the Count of Monte Cristo.
I had hoped to put in
a good word for him.
His Excellency mentioned that
he doesn't have a bank,
...so I thought I should introduce
him to you, Baron.
That was most considerate
of you.
I'm always glad to meet
fine new customers.
Allow me to introduce Baron Danglars, the
most powerful banker in Paris right now.
It is a pleasure to make
your acquaintance.
Look, you missed a spot
over here, too!
You need to be more careful
with Eclipse's grooming.
Yes, Madame.
And never give him anything
but the feed I've specified.
Yes, Madame.
I've received a letter of introduction
and contract papers...
...from the firm of Thomson & French.
To tell you the truth, I'm amazed that they
would act as guarantor for an individual.
They are the largest banking firm
in Eastern Space.
Indeed they are. However, there is one
item in this contract that concerns me.
That concerns you?
According to this, no upper limit
has been set to your line of credit.
In short, it could be interpreted
that my bank...
...would have to indefinitely
continue to provide you...
...with any amount you wished,
no matter how great the sum.
And does that present
a problem?
This is a bit of an
awkward situation.
You say it as if it were nothing, but such
lopsided deals don't exist in this world.
Be that as it may, the firm of Thomson & French
have judged that in my case, they do.
Surely you don't doubt the
validity of this contract?
Not at all, its authenticity has already
been verified. This contract is genuine.
Oh, I see. In which case,
you are saying...
...that it is me that you
are unable to trust.
I got tickets to tonight's
opera from the Count.
About that Count of Monte Cristo fellow...
Apparently, he managed to secure
a box at the opera house.
He's quite a skilled player.
So it would seem.
Why don't we go pay our respects
during intermission tonight?
One, two, three...
Five?
F-Five hundred million?!
I had planned to open an account today
and deposit these.
My intent was to let the interest from
the deposit accrue in the account.
But I see that you
are not interested.
N-Not at all...
You leave me no choice, then.
I shall try another bank.
Please! W-Wait!
Wait...
Lucien sure is a go-getter, coming over to talk
business with your father so early in the day.
You really are a child,
aren't you?
I can't believe you actually
admire a guy like him.
"A guy like him"?
He's our friend!
I've never thought of him
as a friend.
We've been together
since we were kids!
That "friend" of ours
is sleeping with my mother.
We are agreed, then. I will deposit these
in your account right away.
I shall send over a servant later
to pick up my first loan.
Very well.
Incidentally, it has recently
come to my attention...
...that you own the finest horse
in all of Paris, Baron.
Oh, you have an interest
in horses, Count?
English thoroughbreds
in particular.
The thought had occurred to me
to purchase it from you.
Name your price.
Surely you joke!
That horse belongs to my wife.
I have no intention of selling it.
For the right price,
everything is for sale.
I should think that you would
know that better than anyone, Baron.
This is terrible! Monsieur Danglars
has sold Madame's horse!
He sold Eclipse?
Yes, Mademoiselle!
Just now!
They're going
to fight again...
Monsieur Danglars said that he was offered
a huge sum. He seemed very excited.
It was the Count...
What is it?
You're interrupting us.
I'm terribly sorry, Count. This is my wife.
This is the Count of Monte Cristo.
Where is my horse!
Where is my Eclipse?!
I was going to discuss
this with you later.
Count, if you would kindly
excuse us for a moment.
You sold Eclipse?!
Keep your voice down!
Look, don't let this shock you...
That horse was worth 5.8 million Francs,
and the Count bought him for 20 million!
Eclipse was my horse!
Look, that horse
was worth...
This isn't about
the money!
I promised Madame Villefort
that she could use him tomorrow!
You have lots of
other horses!
I refuse to use any horse
but Eclipse!
Get in there and cancel
the deal this instant!
What's this nonsense?
You had no right to sell
my horse!
My good Baroness, if I have upset a beautiful
lady such as yourself, I must apologize.
I had thought that if I offered 60 million,
you would find the amount satisfactory.
But we each have things that are so precious
to us that a price cannot be put upon them.
Please pardon my ineptitude at failing
to take that into consideration.
Oh, my...
That's quite all right.
But just a moment... Did I hear
you say 60 million just now?
Indeed, Madame. I offered
to pay 60 million in gold.
Oh, I see. Please pardon
my silly question.
In that case, I will
take my leave now.
I shall respect Madame's wishes and
do my utmost to remedy the situation.
Count...
Monsieur, were you planning to pocket a
percentage of the profits, even from me?!
You've got it all wrong!
You and your filthy lies!
Come to my
room later!
Come on, Albert,
let's go somewhere.
Shouldn't we
do something?
They're always
like this.
Go faster.
I can't go any faster.
They're the worst...
The worst family,
and the worst father...
You mean the world
to the Baron.
You don't know him
at all, do you?
If the price was right, he'd sell me off
without giving it a second thought.
As long as we stay here, we'll never be able
to get out from under our parents' thumbs.
I want to live
more freely.
I love the piano. I want to play
all over the world.
Eugenie...
I want to live somewhere far away.
Somewhere that my parents can't reach me.
Then let's go.
You and me.
Let's leave home.
Idiot.
Why am I an idiot?
Let's go back. I have to get
fitted for my dress tonight.
I thought you wanted to leave here! Hey!
Hey, where's Valentine?
What about you?
I thought you were coming with Eugenie.
It's true! He even comes
to me in my dreams!
Do you want to know
what he said to me?
What did he say?
Good evening!
Good evening.
I was given an invitation, too,
but I feel a bit out of place.
Not at all.
It looks wonderful on you.
Um... It's a loaner.
But I thought that the Prince's booth had
been sealed up ever since that incident.
It's been 20 years since that
horrible accident, hasn't it?
I heard that someone has put it
on permanent reserve.
It's unnerving, isn't it? It's as if the
late Prince has returned.
Come now, let's stop talking
about such frightful things.
What a handsome gentleman...
Who is the young lady
next to him?
I don't know, but she's so lovely,
isn't she?
Albert, who is
your friend?
Madame!
What?! Don't make
such a racket...
Your horse, Madame!
Eclipse has returned!
What did you say?!
A new set of box seats
was unveiled today.
It must be Monte Cristo.
Where are his seats?
That's...
That's the late Prince's box!
What's the meaning
of this?!
I haven't been informed of
any of the details, Monsieur.
How can this be?!
I can't believe it!
His Excellency the Count of Monte Cristo
ordered me to give this to Madame...
...as both an apology and as
a getting-acquainted gift.
Oh, I don't know what to say!
What a wonderful gift!
Deposit of 4.5 trillion dollars from
Vanderbilt Far East of Cygnus Alpha.
Deposit of 328 trillion pesos from the Space Canal
Corporation in the Union of Northern Sanctuaries.
Deposit of
14.2 billion pounds...
...from Gravity Advanced Materials
of the United Central Emirates.
Deposit after deposit
of foreign currency...
...is being made into the Count
of Monte Cristo's account.
Who the hell
is that man?
Where is he making
all this money?
Oh, the Count of Monte Cristo!
What a magnificent man he is!
What a magnificent man!
Michelle, that man is
hiding something.
I detect no
suspicious activity.
Leave no stone unturned. Run thorough
checks on everyone he does business with.
Understood.
That's the man...
That's the man who...
Hoping to help a friend with the
feelings that he secretly harbors,
...I go to visit Valentine.
But what I witness
there is...
Act 7:
The Secret Flower Garden
Next time on Gankutsuou,
The Count of Monte Cristo, Act 7:
..."The Secret
Flower Garden."
Bide your time,
and hold out hope!